Finding Aid for the Kenneth Gamet Papers LSC.1124
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kenneth Gamet papers
1940-1970
UCLA Library Special Collections
Gamet, Kenneth
LSC.1124
16.5 Linear Feet (33 boxes)
Kenneth Gamet (d.1971) wrote scripts for radio, screen, and television. He also co-founded the Screen Writers Guild. The collection consists of story outlines, treatments, production notes, memoranda, correspondence, radio scripts, television scripts, original screenplays and supporting materials. Television scripts include those for Cheyenne, Zorro, Annie Oakley, and Casey Jones.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Helen Aigner, 1972.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9914704733606533
Biography/History
Gamet wrote scripts for radio, screen, and television; he was a co-founder of the Screen Writers Guild, and scripted more than 50 feature films, concluding with Apache Rifle (1964); he then specialized in telewriting; he died on October 13, 1971 in Los Angeles.
Expanded Biographical Note
Kenneth Gamet was a screenwriter and playwrite who began his career ca. 1936, collaborating during his early years with Don Ryan. Gamet specialized in adventure films, especially westerns. [from Filmlexicon degli autori e delle opere Rome, 1959; TA *PN 1998 A2F5 v. 2]
The collection was transferred from the Theatre Arts Library and consists of 33 boxes of story outlines, treatments, production notes, memoranda, correspondence, radio scripts, television scripts, original screenplays and supporting materials.
Gamet died October 1971 at the age of 64. He was co-founder of the screenwriters' guild. [His obituary appeared in Daily Variety, Thursday October 14, 1971.]
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Story outlines, treatments, production notes, memoranda and correspondence (Boxes 1-12).
Original screenplays and supporting material (Boxes 13-28).
Radio scripts (Boxes 29-31).
Television scripts (Boxes 32-33).
Radio scripts; Television scripts.; Screenplays; Radio writers -- United States -- Archives.; Television writers -- United States -- Archives.; Screenwriters -- United States -- Archives.; Gamet, Kenneth--Archives.
- Story Outlines, Treatments, Production Notes, Memoranda and Correspondence
  - Story outlines, treatments, production notes, memoranda and correspondence. (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12)
- Original Screenplays and Supporting Material
  - North of Nome. (Box 13)
  - Brother Van. (Box 13)
  - Smart blonde. (Box 13)
  - Renegade Canyon. (Box 13)
  - Last of the Comanches (Sabre and the arrow). (Box 14)
  - Trails westward. (Box 14)
  - Sundown. (Box 14)
  - The day the gun died. (Box 14)
  - Coroner Creek. (Box 15)
  - The black widow. (Box 15)
  - Sunset rim. (Box 15)
  - Flat-top (A lady comes home). (Box 16)
  - Strange alibi. (Box 16)
  - Flying Tigers. (Box 16)
  - The poor nut. (Box 17)
  - War cry. (Box 17)
  - Wild fury. (Box 17)
  - Flowing gold. (Box 17)
  - Fly-away baby. (Box 17)
  - Ten wanted men. (Box 18)
  - Pittsburgh. (Box 18)
  - The king of the Comstock. (Box 18)
  - Iceland patrol. (Box 18)
  - The stranger wore a gun (I ride alone). (Box 19)
  - It takes nerve. (Box 19)
  - Outlaw's code. (Box 19)
  - Inside story. (Box 19)
  - Flying leathernecks. (Box 19)
  - Canadian Pacific. (Box 19)
  - The western story. (Box 20)
  - Khyber Pass. (Box 20)
  - Trigger finger Freddy. (Box 20)
  - Mixed nuts. (Box 20)
  - Nancy Drew - smart girl. (Box 20)
  - Man in the saddle. (Box 20)
  - A lady comes home. (Box 20)
  - Adventure in Silverado (Adventures of Silverado). (Box 20)
  - The password to Larkspur Lane. (Box 20)
  - Domino. (Box 21)
  - The defense rests. (Box 21)
  - The case of the dangerous dowager. (Box 21)
  - The marshal of Medicine Bend. (Box 21)
  - Citizen soldier. (Box 21)
  - Military Police story. (Box 22)
  - To the last Marine. (Box 22)
  - Dangerous Nancy Drew. (Box 22)
  - Bomber's moon. (Box 22)
  - Tampico. (Box 23)
  - The singing cop. (Box 23)
  - Sittin' pretty. (Box 23)
  - Santa Fe. (Box 23)
  - Juke girl. (Box 23)
  - Doolins of Oklahoma (The Doolin gang). (Box 24)
  - The people's mouthpiece. (Box 24)
  - The return of Doctor X. Part I. (Box 24)
  - The last headline. (Box 24)
  - Lawless. (Box 24)
  - Quintuplet story. (Box 25)
  - The last posse (The posse). (Box 25)
  - Highway west (Highway 99). (Box 25)
  - Guadalcanal diary. (Box 25)
  - You can't get away with murder (Chalked out). (Box 25)
  - Tugboad Annie sails again. (Box 25)
  - The smiling ghost. (Box 25)
  - Blonde ice. (Box 26)
  - South of Pago Pago. (Box 26)
  - She stayed kissed. (Box 26)
  - Torchy plays with dynamite (Dead or alive). (Box 26)
  - Many brave men. (Box 26)
  - Fighting Coast Guard (Fighting U.S.Coast Guard). (Box 26)
  - Betrayal from the East. (Box 27)
  - Canadian Pacific. (Box 27)
  - Call of the North. (Box 27)
  - The freebooter. (Box 27)
  - Crosswinds. (Box 28)
  - Silver rock. (Box 28)
  - Showdown in Deadwood. (Box 28)
  - Hit Parade of 1945. (Box 28)
  - Santa Fe passage. (Box 28)
  - Pride of the commandos. (Box 28)
  - The long watch. (Box 28)
  - The maverick queen. (Box 28)
- Radio Scripts
  - Growin' up (Episodes 1-62). (Box 29)
  - Growin' up (Episodes 63-125). (Box 30)
  - James Stewart as The six-shooter. (Box 31)
  - Binnacle Bill (Episodes 1-2). (Box 31)
  - The bachelor girls. (Box 31)
  - The christening of Koh-I-Nur. (Box 31)
  - The Lotery diamond. (Box 31)
  - The Piggot diamond. (Box 31)
  - A piece of glass. (Box 31)
  - The witch's cauldron. (Box 31)
  - Money talks. (Box 31)
  - Little Bohemia. (Box 31)
  - Bubbles. (Box 31)
  - Judy. (Box 31)
  - The girl friend. (Box 31)
- Television Scripts
  - Cheyenne. "The imposter." (Box 32)
  - Cheyenne. "Hero of the town." (Box 32)
  - Zorro (Episode 2). (Box 32)
  - New York confidential. The New Citizen, 1959 (Box 32)
  - Jody. "Outlaw's boy." (Box 32)
  - Stagecoast west. "The bold whip." (Box 32)
  - The westerner. "Duel at Lockwood." (Box 32)
  - The Kale boys. "The men from Tallahassee." (Box 32)
    Scope and Content
    Episode of Talahassee 7000.
  - The Kale boys. "Stakeout." (Box 32)
  - Restless Gun. Thicker than water., 1957 (Box 32)
  - Straightaway. "The tin Caesar.", 1961 (Box 32)
  - Annie Oakley. "Whiphand." (Box 32)
  - Annie Oakley. "The welcome trap." (Box 32)
  - Annie Oakley. "Miracle of the gun." (Box 32)
  - Buckskin. "The ballad of the Gabe Pruitt." (Box 32)
  - Colt .45. "Breakthrough.", 1960 (Box 32)
  - Colt .45. "The garnet-studded concha." (Box 32)
  - "The thin rope." (Box 32)
- Casey Jones Series
  - no.4176: "The President's Special." (Box 33)
  - no.4178: "The run to Deadwood." (Box 33)
  - no.4179: "Prison train." (Box 33)
  - no.4182: "The lost train." (Box 33)
  - no.4184: "Satan's will." (Box 33)
  - no.4186: "The marauders." (Box 33)
  - no.4189: "One-way ticket." (Box 33)
  - no.4192: "Star witness." (Box 33)
  - no.4198: "Iron men." (Box 33)
  - no.4203: "Command performance." (Box 33)
  - no.4210: "The treasure of Sam Bass." (Box 33)
  - no.4214: "Storm warning." (Box 33)
  - no.4228: "The Dutch clock." (Box 33)
  - no.4230: "Hard luck train." (Box 33)
  - no.4247: "The silk train." (Box 33)
  - no.4266: "Honeymoon Express." (Box 33)